Nora England Papers
Nettie Lee Benson Latin American Collection
- Series V: Fieldwork and Analysis
  - Subseries I: Field Notebooks
    - Quiché 1, 1986 January 23-April 1 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Quiché 2, 1986 April 3-May 6 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Ostuncalco Mam 86-1, 1986 July 29-July 30 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Mayan 88 - 1, 1988 February 11-February 18 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Maya 88 - 2, 1988 March 22-April 18 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Maya 88 - 3, 1988 April 18-July 29 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Maya 89 - 1, 1989 January 27-April 7 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Maya 89 - 2, 1989 April 17-June 3 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Maya 89 - 3, 1989 July 4-July 15 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Kaqchikel, 1991 October 28-November 9 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - 1991 (3 pages), 2009 (k'chee'), 1991 November 6-2009 October 17 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Teko, 2003 July 7-July 16 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Gujarati Transcription, 1969 April 10-May 31 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - North Florida Negro Dialect - Book 1, 1970 February 4 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - North Florida Negro Dialect - Book 2, 1970 February 4 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - North Florida Negro Dialect - Book 3, 1970 February 4 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - North Florida Negro Dialect - Book 4, 1970 February 6 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Aymara, Fall 1969 - Book I, 1969 September 18-October 14 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Aymara, Fall 1969 - Book II, 1969 October 16-December 8 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Aymara, Winter 1971 - Book III, 1971 January 11-June 26 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Aymara, 1971 - Book IV, 1971 July 1-July 8 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Choctaw, January 1976 - Book I, 1976 January 5-February (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Choctaw, March 1976 - Book II, 1976 March (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Igbo, January 1978, 1978 January 26-April 20 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Kusaal, Spring 1983, 1983 January 21-September 22 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Kusaal, Spring 1983 - Book 1, 1983 January 24-March 14 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Kusaal, Spring 1983 - Book 2, 1983 March 14-September 6 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Kusaal, Spring 1983 - Book 3, 1983 September 8-October 18 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Kusaal, Spring 1983 - Book 4, 1983 October 18-December 15 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Punchcards for Mam Directionals, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Subseries II: Field Notes and Analysis
    - Subsubseries: Teco
      - Teco, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Textos de Teko de Mazapa, Grabados, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Teco Directionals, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Teco Texts, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Teco Texts, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Teco, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Teco, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Words and Glottal Stops in 2 Dialects of Teko, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Subsubseries: Mam
      - Mam San Juan Word List, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Word Lists, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - Mam de San Juan Ostuncalco, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Mam Ixtahuacán Materials, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Mam Texts, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Mam Monosyllables, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Mam Texts, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Mam Texts, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Mam Data, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Mam Texts, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Mam Directional Prefixes, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Mam Directional Prefixes, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Mam Transitive Verbs, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Mam Transitive Verbs, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Mam Data on Food, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Dictionary Checking Procedures for Mam, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Mam Dictionary, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Mam OST Sketch, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Mam Notes, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Informe de Analisis de Mam, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Mam Analysis, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Mam Analysis, Report, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Mam Database, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Mam Analysis Group of Dialects, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Thematic Pedro, Mam, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Mam Interview with Roberto, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Fonología Mam, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Mam Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Mam Phonology, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Mam Data, undated (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Mam Fragments, undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
      - Notes on Voice, Mam, undated (Box 18, Folder 25)
      - Possessive Mam Data, undated (Box 18, Folder 26)
      - Affect Words, Mam, undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
      - Measure Words, Mam, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
      - Miscellaneous Mam Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
      - Mam Positionals, undated (Box 18, Folder 30)
      - Mam Derivation, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - Mam Lexicostatistics, undated (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - Mam Ergativity, undated (Box 18, Folder 33)
      - Mam Directional Data, undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
      - Mam Adjectives, undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
      - Mam - Ixtahuacán, Verbs, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Subsubseries: Other Languages
      - Jaqaru, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 37)
      - Tecpán, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 38)
      - Cakchiquel Swadesh List, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 39)
- Series VI: Grants, Fellowships, and Funding Materials
  - Subseries I: National Science Foundation
    - National Science Foundation, Grant: Analysis of Ixil Mayan Texts, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - National Science Foundation, Grant: Mamean (Mayan) Comparative Syntax-1, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - National Science Foundation, Grant: Mamean (Mayan) Comparative Syntax-2, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II: Fulbright
    - Fulbright Award, 1988-1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Subseries III: MacArthur Fellowship Award
    - Congratulations Letters, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Press, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Official Correspondence, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Subseries IV: Misc Grants
    - Política Lingüística Grant, Dirección General de Educación Bilignue Intercultural (DIGEBI), 2001 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - IRB Horseshit (Collaborative Institutional Training Initiative), 2014 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Series VII: Miscellaneous Personal Papers
  - Proyecto de becas en apoyo a la formación profesional de la población maya y su proyección a las comunidades de origen, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Ixkeem Nora England birthday, 2021 November 6 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Guaján - Propuesta IAF: Metodología del proceso de enseñanza-aprendizaje en la educación no formal de las ONG mayas, CISMA, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Carlota S. Smith Obituary, 2009 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Series VIII: Clippings, Maps, and Glyphs
  - Subseries I: Clippings
    - News Clippings, 1983-2011 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Clippings and Book Review, 1992-2003 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Clippings on OKMA Book Presentation, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Guatemalan Civil War Clippings, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Subseries II: Maps
    - Maps of Guatemala and Mexico, circa 1980s (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Maps, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Subseries III: Glyphs
    - Glyphs, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
- Series IX: Audiovisual
  - Subseries I: Photographs
    - Miami, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Guatemala, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Guatemala, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Negative Prints, Guatemala, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Guatemala, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Narciso's Visit, 1979 October (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Taller Maya IV, Palenque, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Guatemala, circa 1970s (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Guatemala, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Taller Maya V, Guatemala City, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Guatemala, 1980 January (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Guatemala, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - New York, 1986 May (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - CIRMA, Guatemala, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Guatemala, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Guatemala, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Benigno Robles Reyes, circa 1980s (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Guatemala Ruins, circa 1980s (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Guatemala, circa 1980s (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Guatemala, circa 1980s (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Antigua, Guatemala, circa 1980s (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Guatemala, 1991 July (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Guatemala, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Panel, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Antigua, Guatemala, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Guatemala, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Guatemala, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Semana Santa, OKMA, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Guatemala, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Guatemala, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Presentacion de Libros, 1999 September 6 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Guatemala, Tikal, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Antigua, Guatemala, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Guatemala, 2000 March (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Austin, Texas, 2006 February (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Austin, Texas, circa 2000s (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Family, circa 2000s (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Misc. 1, circa 2000s (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Australia, 2018 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Australia, 2018 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - University of Iowa Portrait of Nora England, undated (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Misc. 2, circa 1970s (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Subseries II: Photograph Slides
    - San Jorge Laguna, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Guatemala and Alaska, 1971-1978 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - El Salvador, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Jocotenango Procession, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Semana Santa, Antigua, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Guatemala, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Misc., 1972 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Ixtahuacan, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Antigua, Guatemala, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Ixiuchay, Zaculeo, Kaunal, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Guatemala, 1972-1975 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Copan, Honduras, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Wedding in Guatemala, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Chichicastenango, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Santa Catarina, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Lake Atitlan and Santiago, Atitlan, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Misc. People, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Misc., 1973-1979 (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - Choctaw Day Mississippi State University, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - Noxubee Refuge, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Misc. Mississippi, 1976-1978 (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - Florida, 1976-1978 (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - Choctaw Lake, 1976-1978 (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - Ruins, Antigua, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - Misc. Mexico Ruins, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Subseries III: CD-R, Photographs
    - Disc 1: Cholotio, Guatemala, Graduacion de Telma, Somaya, Waykan, 2003 (Box 21)
    - Disc 2: Jess and Casey, Antigua, Guatemala, 2005 July (Box 21)
    - Disc 3: Jess Clearman, Casey Breves with Telma, 2005 July 8 (Box 21)
    - Disc 4: Taller de Complementacion, 2006 (Box 21)
    - Disc 5: Cholotio/Documentacion, undated (Box 21)
    - Disc 6: No Title, undated (Box 21)
    - Disc 7: No Title, undated (Box 21)
    - Disc 8: Photos 5-1-03, undated (Box 21)
    - Disc 9: No Title, undated (Box 21)
    - Disc 10: CILLA II, Jon Landabury "Expresion Gramatical de lo Epistemico", PDF file, 2005 (Box 21)
  - Subseries IV: CD Rom (Box 21)
    - Disc 10: Taitadehaan, Western Mono Ways of Speaking, 2002 (Box 21)
    - Disc 11: The Disappearing Sounds of the World's Endangered Languages, 2005 (Box 21)
    - Disc 13: Este es Mi Canto, Ya'stzun Wetz Nb'itz and booklet, 2017 (Box 21)
    - Disc 14: Atlas Linguistico de Guatemala, undated (Box 21)
    - Disc 15: Enseñanza de la Gramatica Maya, undated (Box 21)
    - Disc 16: Del Silencio a la Memoria Revelaciones del Archivo Historico de la Policia Nacional, undated (Box 21)
    - Disc 17: Taax Ketlaan Ti'alu Beeta'al Maayak K'aayo'ob, 1er. Concurso de la Cancion en Lengua Maya and booklet, undated (Box 21)
    - Disc 18: Kaufman Etymologies, Mayan, undated (Box 21)
  - Subseries V: Minidisc (Box 21)
    - Unlabeled Mini Disc, undated (Box 21)
  - Subseries VI: Tapes
    - Cassette 1: Side 1 Sokhata hica nasoba Barry Jim (Pearl River) 027/Side 2 Yakni Imato Catherine Solomon (Conehatla) 28-58 copy 2, 1976 March (Box 21)
    - Cassette 2: Side 1 Cahtat kanot pomma alatos maya/Side 2 Jake York (25 years) Pearl River 0-46 copy 1, 1976 February 24 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 3: Side 1 First Panel: Papel de Linguistas del Extranjero en la Ling. Maya/Side 2 panel, 1989 June 22 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 4: Side 1 Second Panel: Papel de Linguistas del Extranjero en la Ling. Maya/Side 2 panel, 1989 June 22 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 5: Side 1: audio on this side, but no writing/Side 2 Mam-Ixtlahuacan, undated (Box 21)
    - Cassette 6: Side 1 Cakchiquel phonology/Side 2 Cakchiquel Text cuento re jun aclun yalan vkik'ot ag'awinag rawex, 1980 August (Box 21)
    - Cassette 7: Side 1 Mam de San Pedro Roberto/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1984 May 17 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 8: Side 1 Narciso Cojtí-Caleehiguel Story/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1979 October 20 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 9: Side 1 phonetics chart/Side 2 nothing written on it, undated (Box 21)
    - Cassette 10: Side 1 Ruby Thomas/Side 2 nothing written on it, undated (Box 21)
    - Cassette 11: Side 1 The Corpus Contrasts Monotony Tests/Side 2 Tones in frames Consonants Vowels Folktale Tone Drills; Gleason Chapter 18 Phonemic Fieldwork-Ewe, undated (Box 21)
    - Cassette 12: Side 1 All Things Considered Open Forum in Miami--Refugees and Language/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1980 March-1982 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 13: Side 1 Awinash Bhatkar/Side 2 nothing written on it, undated (Box 21)
    - Cassette 14: Side 1 Lists/Side 2 Lists, 1983 April 4-May 12 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 15: Side 1 Kusaal/Side 2 Kusaal, September 1, no year (Box 21)
    - Cassette 16: Side 1 Kusaal/Side 2 Kusaal, August 30, no year (Box 21)
    - Cassette 17: Side 1 Kusaal: Robert, Rita, Amerlia (8 1/2 mos). Then story by Rita./Side 2 nothing written on this side, 1983 October (Box 21)
    - Cassette 18: Side 1 Kusaal Text 5 Robert Agunga/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1983 September 27 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 19: Side 1 Kusaal Tape 1 Recorded MONO on side A, verb paradigms, word list, story of chief's daughter, Robert Agunga/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1983 March 15 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 20: Side 1 Kusaal 113: 271/Side 2 9/6, undated (Box 21)
    - Cassette 21: Side 1 Kusaal Rev Edward Akugri and Rita Agunga/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1984 August 14 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 22: Side 1 Jordan, pregnancy/Side 2 Jordan pregnancy, 1970 February 4 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 23: Side 1 Jordan, pregnancy/Side 2 Jordan, pregnancy, 1970 February 4 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 24: Side 1 pregnancy, Evelyn Star, Annie Nita/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1970 February 6 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 25: Side 1 pregnancy, Evelyn Star, Annie Nita/Side 2 pregnancy, Evelyn Star, Annie Nita, Bertha Harris, 1970 February 6 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 26: Side 1 pregnancy, Dr. Holden/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1970 February 7 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 27: Side 1 Roseanna T. (9 mins talk); transcribe for two weeks/Side 2 Roseanna Tubby, 1977 January (Box 21)
    - Cassette 28: Side 1 Eddie Gibson/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1977 January (Box 21)
    - Cassette 29: Side 1 nothing written on it/Side 2 nothing written on it; recording of a linguistics class in English, undated (Box 21)
    - Cassette 30: Side 1 Teco 85-1/Side 2 nothing written on it; 0-34 Techitan taped on Paul Stevenson "The Mirror;" side B empty, 1984 June 7 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 31: Side 1 Tectitan Teco Cuestionario Ling-II/Side 2 Tectitan Texts, 1985 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 32: Side 1 Tectitan Teco-Cuestionario Ling II/Side 2 nothing written on it, undated (Box 21)
    - Cassette 33: Side 1 Teco/Tectitan Cuestionario/Side 2 Teco/Tectitan Cuestionario, 1985 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 34: Side 1 Teco/Tectitan Cuestionario/Side 2 Teco/Tectitan Cuestionario, 1985 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 35: Side 1 Teco Teco word list/Side 2 Teco stories; Teco 1, 1984 June (Box 21)
    - Cassette 36: Side 1 Margarito Hernández text/Side 2 nothing written on it; Teco 2, 1984 February 25 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 37: Side 1 Ty + C words (panasonic)/Side 2 nothing written on it; Teco 3, undated (Box 21)
    - Cassette 38: Side 1 Teco 4-stories/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1984 April 4 (Box 21)
    - Cassette 39: Side 1 Teco 5-Texts/Side 2 nothing written on it, 1984 May (Box 21)
    - Cassette 40: Side 1 Teco 6: stories/Side 2 Teco 6: stories, 1984 May (Box 21)